Register of the Harry S. Kantor Papers, 1948-1977.
Hoover Institution Archives
- U.S. DEPARTMENT OF LABOR. OFFICE OF RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT. 1948-1973
  - Special studies (Folder 3)
  - Staff organization and responsibilities (Folder 4)
  - State-Federal Technical Services, 1964 (Folder 5)
  - State Labor Agency Assistance Act (Folder 6)
  - State labor standards, 1966 (Folder 7)
  - Statement by the Secretary of Labor in introduction to the Manpower Report, February 1968 (Folder 8)
  - Stewart, Charles, "Price Stabilization - Some Questions for Labor Programs," memorandum, March 28, 1968 (Folder 9)
  - Systems Development Advisory Committee (Folder 10)
  - Task Force on the Fall Civil Rights Conference, August 1965 (Folder 11)
  - "Task Force on Manpower Conservation: Work Program and Work Schedule," October 1963 (Folder 12)
  - Technological innovation, 1968-1973 (Folder 13)
  - "Toward a Society without Fear," May 1968 (Folder 14)
  - Training in industry
    - General (Folder 15)
    - BAT plans for an improved survey on (Folder 16)
  - Training programs (Folder 17)
  - Trips (Folder 18)
  - Underemployment (Folder 19)
  - Unemployed workers, improving income maintenance for (Folder 20)
  - Unemployment
    - General (Folder 21)
    - Long-term (Folder 22)
  - Unemployment insurance (Box 20., Folder 1-2)
  - U.S. Department of Commerce. Patent Office. Report by the Patent System Panel of the Commerce Technical Advisory Board, February 11, 1964 (Folder 3)
  - U.S. Department of Labor
    - Department-Wide Data Systems Study, Summary of Information Systems Status and Requirements, September 1966 (Folder 4)
    - Bureau of Employment Security. "Economic Assumptions for Fiscal Year 1969," January 1968 (Folder 5)
    - Bureau of Labor Statistics
      - "Hours of Work and Output," 1948 (Folder 6)
      - "Long-Range Projections of Labor Force," Denis F. Johnston, September 1967 (Folder 7)
      - "Reasons for Nonparticipation in the Labor Force," Robert L. Stein, Monthly Labor Review, July 1967 (Folder 8)
    - Manpower Administration
      - Bureau of Employment Security. "Economic Assumptions for Fiscal Year 1970." (Folder 9)
      - Divisions of Planning
        - "Defining and Identifying the Disadvantaged," November 1967 (Folder 10)
        - "The Level and Mix of the FY 1969 Manpower Development Program," September 1967 (Folder 11)
      - Office of Manpower Policy, Evaluation, and Research. "Illustrative Cost/Constraint Analysis in the United States Unemployment Insurance Area," December 1967 (Folder 12)
    - Office of Manpower, Automation, and Training. Division of Special Programs. "Experimental and Demonstration Programs under the Manpower Development and Training Act of 1962: A Two Year Summary (1963-65)." (Folder 13)
  - United States Employment Service (Folder 14)
  - Vocational training (Folder 15)
  - Wage and employment (Folder 16)
  - Wage and Hour and Public Contracts (Folder 17)
  - Wage and labor standards (Box 21., Folder 1-3)
  - Wages and employment (Folder 4)
  - Wages and unemployment, 1965 (Folder 5)
  - Walsh-Healey Act (Folder 6-7)
  - Weaver, John D., "The Department of Labor," reprint, Holiday Magazine, 1963 (Folder 8)
  - Wirtz, W. Willard
    - "Experience of Other Countries in Dealing with Technological Unemployment," August 1963 (Folder 9)
    - "A Human Resources Development Program," address before the Mayor's Conference on Employment, Chicago, November 3, 1965 (Folder 10)
    - "Youth - It's Freedom and Responsibility, " address before the Greater Hartford Forum, Hartford Connecticut, November 10, 1965 (Folder 11)
  - Womens Bureau
    - 1964 (Folder 12)
    - Planning goals for 1967-1971 (Folder 13)
  - Womens Bureau and Childrens Bureau Joint Conference on Day Care Centers, n.d. (Folder 14)
  - Work programs for adults, 1965 (Folder 15)
  - Youth, employment of (Folder 16-17)
  - Youth with police or prison records (Folder 18)
  - Youth with police or prison records (Box 22., Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 2-3)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1950-1976
  - Allied Civil Group, Silver Spring, Maryland (Box 22., Folder 4)
  - Baumol, William J., Welfare Economics and the Theory of the State. Harvard University Press, 1965 (Folder 5)
  - Berelson, Bernard and Steiner, Gary A., Human Behavior, n.d., experts (Folder 6)
  - Biographical data
    - General (Folder 7)
    - Earnings and leave record (Folder 8)
    - Executive listing (Folder 9)
    - Promotions, transfers, work assignments (Folder 10)
    - Retirement (Folder 11)
  - Bollay, William, "Some Techniques for Stimulating Creative Engineering and New Product Development," AIAA Student Journal, Vol. 6, No. 2, April 1968 (Folder 12)
  - Booher, Edward E., "The Decades Ahead from a Publisher's View," June 22, 1967 (Folder 13)
  - Bowman, Mary Jean, "Schultz, Denison and the Contribution of 'Eds' to National Income Growth," Journal of Political Economy, October 1964 (Folder 14)
  - Bowman, Raymond T., Statement before the Subcommittee on Statistics of the Joint Economic Committee, June 7, 1967 (Folder 15)
  - Brandt, Karl, "Guidelines for a Constructive Revision of Agricultural Policy in the Coming Decade," August 25, 1960 (Folder 16)
  - Brimmer, Andrew F., "Economic Progress in Black and White," remarks at the Houston Citizens Chamber of Commerce, January 21, 1966 (Folder 17)
  - Bruner, Jerome S., "Culture, Politics and Pedagogy," n.d. (Folder 18)
  - Buchanan, James M., and Tullock, Gordon, "The Calculus of Consent-Logical Foundations of Constitutional Democracy," 1962 (Box 23., Folder 1)
  - Bugliarello, George, "Large Socio-Technological Systems: Human Conflict and Human Design," June 1969 (Folder 2)
  - Burck, Gilbert, "The Still-Bright Promise of the Historic Transition to the Service Society Raises Questions about Future Economic Growth," Fortune, October 1968 (Folder 3)
  - California. Santa Clara and San Mateo Counties. San Francisquito Creek. Report of Survey for Flood Control and Allied Purposes, n.d. (Folder 4)
  - California State Legislature. Senate Fact Finding Committee on Labor and Welfare. Excerpts from the Hearing on agricultural labor, January 23-27, 1960 (Folder 5)
  - Campano, Arnaldo R., "The Minimum Wage Act in Argentina," International Labor Review, Vol. 94, No. 3, September 1966 (Folder 6)
  - Carey, William D., "Budgeting Problems in Research and Development," October 28, 1965 (Folder 7)
  - Clague, Ewan, "The Coordination and Integration of Government Statistical Programs," June 8, 1967 (Folder 8)
  - Columbia University (Folder 9-10)
  - Curti, Merle, "Intellectuals and Other People," The American Historical Review, Vol. LX, No. 2, January 1955 (Folder 11)
  - Douty, H. M., "A Note on the British National Incomes Commission," Monthly Labor Review, September 1963 (Folder 12)
  - Drugs (Folder 13)
  - Dubos, Rene, "Biological Individuality," Columbia Forum Spring 1969 (Folder 14)
  - Earnings and salary (Folder 15)
  - Eckstein, Otto, "Goal and Strategies in the War on Poverty," paper delivered at the West Virginia University Conference on Poverty Amidst Affluence, May 7, 1965 (Folder 16)
  - Education and students (Folder 17-18)
  - Education and students (Box 24., Folder 1-2)
  - Employed inventor (Folder 3)
  - Employment for criminals (Folder 4)
  - Evans, W. Duane, "Productivity and Wages," 1953 (Folder 5)
  - Falkland (Folder 6)
  - Family planning (Folder 7)
  - Faunce, William A., "Job Satisfaction and the Meaning of Work," n.d. (Folder 8)
  - Fazer, Willard, "Applying Operations Research and the Management Sciences to Planning, Programming, and Budgeting in Non-Defense Agencies," April 25, 1966 (Folder 9)
  - Federal Council for Science and Technology Committee on Government Patent Policy, Government Patent Policy Study, Final Report, Volume I, May 1968 (Folder 10)
  - Federal spending (Folder 11)
  - Flanagan, Robert J., "Disguised Unemployment and the Structural Hypothesis," Industrial Relations, Vol. 5, No. 1, October 1965 (Folder 12)
  - Forest Glen Incinerator, Walter Reed Army Medical Center (Folder 13-14)
  - Forest Glen Incinerator, Walter Reed Army Medical Center (Box 25., Folder 1)
  - Franklin, N. N., "The Concept and Measurement of 'Minimum Living Standards,' reprint, International Labour Review, Vol. 95, No. 4, April 1967 (Folder 2)
  - Friedman, Milton, "Intentions vs. Results in Economic Policy," substance of remarks at Columbia University Club, New York, November 18, 1964 (Folder 3)
  - Glancy, David M., "Utilization of Economic Analysis by State Highway Departments," January 1964 (Folder 4)
  - Goodman, Elliot R., "The Soviet Design for a World State," 1960 (Folder 5)
  - Gordon, Kermit, "Research Opportunities in Applying Rational Calculation to Federal Expenditures," October 2, 1965 (Folder 6)
  - Gross, Bertram M., "National Planning: Findings and Fallacies," Public Administration Review, December 1965 (Folder 7)
  - Gude, Congressman Gilbert (Folder 8)
  - Handler, Philip, "The Young Scientist - Hour of Decision," address at the Science Talent Search for the Westinghouse Science Scholarships and Awards, Washington, D.C., March 3, 1969 (Folder 9)
  - Harvard University
    - Graduate School of Business. Formal Planning Systems - 1968. Boston, 1968 (Folder 10)
    - The University and the City, 1969 (Folder 11)
  - Hathaway, Dale, "Migration from Agriculture: The Historical Record and Its Meaning, " 1959 (Folder 12)
  - Health care (Folder 13)
  - Herzberg, Frederick, "One More Time: How Do You Motivate Employees," article, Harvard Business Review, January/February 1968 (Folder 14)
  - Hospitalization benefits and costs (Folder 15)
  - Hughes, H. Stuart, "Is the Intellectual Obsolete?" n.d. (Folder 16)
  - Internal Revenue Service (Folder 17)
  - International Labour Organisation. Advisory Committee on Salaried Employees and Professional Workers.
    - Fourth session, 1957 (Folder 18)
    - Fifth session, 1958 (Folder 19)
  - International Science Fair, 1961-1969 (Folder 20)
  - Inventor and inventions (Folder 21)
  - Johnson, Howard W., "Education for Management and Technology in the 1970s," 1968 (Box 26., Folder 1)
  - Kantor, Frederick William (Folder 2)
  - Kendrick, John W., "The Wage-Productivity-Price Issue," reprint, California Management Review, Vol. II, No. 3, Spring 1960 (Folder 3)
  - Kerr, Clark, "New Challenges to the College and University," n.d. (Folder 4)
  - Kershaw, Joseph A., "The Need for Better Planning and Coordination Manpower," n.d. (Folder 5)
  - Kissinger, Henry A., "Central Issues of American Foreign Policy," n.d. (Folder 6)
  - Kruskal, William, "The Committee on National Statistics,' Science, Vol. 180, June 22, 1973 (Folder 7)
  - Kuhn, James W., "The Misuse of Education - The Problem of Schooling for Employment," May 6, 1969 (Folder 8)
  - Lampman, Robert J., "Approaches to the Reduction of Poverty," paper delivered at the 77th Annual Meeting of the American Economic Association, Chicago, December 30, 1964 (Folder 9)
  - Leontieff, Wassily, "On Assignment of Patent Rights on Inventions Made Under Government Research Contracts," reprint, Harvard Law Review, Vol. 77, No. 3, January 1964 (Folder 10)
  - Levine, Abraham, "Cost-Benefit Analysis and Social Welfare," Welfare in Review, February 1966 (Folder 11)
  - Lewis, Edward E. (Folder 12)
  - Luchterhand, Elmer and Sydiaha, Daniel, "Choice in Human Affairs - An Application to Aging-Accident-Illness Program," 1966 (Folder 13)
  - MacBean, Alasdair I., "Wrong Diagnosis - Export Instability and Economic Development," reprint, The Economist, May 13, 1967 (Folder 14)
  - McCreary, Edward A., "That New Federal Budgeting System," Think, March-April 1966 (Folder 15)
  - Maryland School of Art and Design (Folder 16)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology (Folder 17)
  - Mechner, Francis (Folder 18)
  - Mesthene, Emmanuel G., "How Technology Will Shape the Future," 1968 (Folder 19)
  - Middle East, events in, 1973 (Folder 20)
  - Mills, Wilbur, "Financing Health Care of the Aged," speech, Downtown Litle Rock Arkansas, Lion's Clubs, December 2, 1964 (Folder 21)
  - Mogulof, Melvin B., "The Use of Social Theory in Federal Prevention Program," reprint, The American Behavioral Scientist, Vol. IX, Nos. 4/5, December 1965/January 1966 (Folder 22)
  - Moore, Geoffrey H., "Some Needed Improvements in Economic Statistics," reprint, The American Statistician, December 1967 (Folder 23)
  - Motheral, Joe R., "The Competitive Position of Southern Agriculture," February 1, 1954 (Folder 24)
  - Moynihan, Daniel Patrick
    - "A Family Policy," reprint, America, September 18, 1965 (Folder 25)
    - "Nirvana Now," reprint, The American Scholar, Vol. 36, No. 4, Autumn 1967 (Folder 26)
    - "The Presidency and the Press," article, Commentary, March 1971 (Folder 27)
    - "Who Gets in the Army?" article, The New Republic, November 5, 1966 (Folder 28)
  - National Foundation for Higher Education (Folder 29)
  - National Planning Association, "Program Appraisal in the Federal Government," December 1965 (Folder 30)
  - Neilan, Edwin P., "Training - One Solution to the Unemployment Problem," reprint, Training Directors Journal, November 1963 (Folder 31)
  - Okun, Arthur M., "Statistics for Effective Public Policy," statement before the Subcommittee on Economic Statistics of the Joint Economic Committee, June 8, 1967 (Folder 32)
  - Patent Reform Act of 1967 (Box 27., Folder 1)
  - Patents (Folder 2)
  - Payton, Benjamin F., "The President, the Social Experts, and the Ghetto: An Analysis of an Engineering Strategy in Civil Rights," n.d. (Folder 3)
  - Philippine Islands
    - An Act to Establish a Minimum Wage Law, and for Other Purposes, n.d. (Folder 4)
    - An Act to Promote the Well-Being of Tenants (Aparceros) in Agricultural Lands Devoted to the Production of Rice and to Regulate the Relations between Them and the Landlords of Said Lands, and for Other Purposes, 1946 (Folder 5)
    - Department of Labor
      - "Comments on Judge Roldan's Proposed Bill for the Minimum Wage Bill," January 18, 1951, submitted to the House Committee on Labor (Folder 6)
      - Wage Administration Service, First Report of the Wage Administration Service, June 1 to September 30, 1951 (Folder 7)
    - Fair labor practices (Folder 8-9)
    - House of Representatives. Third Special Sessions. An Act Fixing the Maximum and Minimum Daily Wages of Agricultural and Industrial Laborers. Introduced by Congressman De Leon, N.d. (Folder 10)
    - Minimum Wage Bill (Folder 11)
    - Minimum Wage Law (Folder 12-13)
    - Minimum Wage Law (Box 28., Folder 1)
    - Morabe, Emiliano (Folder 2)
    - Senate. Second Congress. Third Special Session. An Act to Promote a Healthy Development of Labor Unionism in the Phllippines. Introduced by Senator Magalona. N.d. (Folder 3)
  - Philippine Islands
    - Social Security Bill, 1950-1951 (Folder 4)
    - Statistics of Enforcement Activity, July 1 to September 30, 1951 (Folder 5)
  - Planning-Programming-Budgeting System (PPBS) (Folder 6)
  - Poverty (Folder 7)
  - President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy, "Industrial Relations and Labor Market Policies in Sweden," n.d. (Folder 8)
  - President's Science Advisory Committee, Scientific Progress, Universities, and the Federal Government, November 15, 1960 (Folder 9)
  - President's Task Force on Manpower Conservation, "One Third of a Nation - A Report on Young Men Found Unqualified for Military Service," January 1, 1964 (Folder 10)
  - Quade, E. S., "Systems Analysis Techniques for Planning - Programming, - Budgeting," March 1966 (Folder 11)
  - Rainwater, Lee
    - "Crucible of Identity: The Negro Lower-Class Family," Daedalus, Winter 1966 (Folder 12)
    - "Open Letter on White Justice and the Riots," Trans-Action, n.d. (Folder 13)
  - Ranulf, Svend, "Moral Indignation and Middle Class Psychology - A Sociological Study," 1964 (Folder 14)
  - Republican National Committee, "Red Herring and Whitewash the Record of Communism in the Government," October 1950 (Folder 15)
  - Ruben, Samuel, "The Motivations of Michael Faraday," n.d (Folder 16)
  - Schultz, Theodore W., "Investing in Poor People: An Economists View," December 1964 (Folder 17)
  - Science and technology (Folder 18-19)
  - Science and technology (Box 29., Folder 1-7)
  - Security investigation data (Folder 8)
  - Shannon, Lyle W., "Social Factors in Economic Growth," Current Sociology, Vol. VI, No. 3, 1957 (Box 30., Folder 1)
  - Shultz, George, Statement before the Committee on Ways and Means on the Family Assistance Act of 1969, n.d. (Folder 2)
  - Singleton, W. T., "Ergonomics and Job Satisfaction," n.d. (Folder 3)
  - Sloan Foundation grants, 1970 (Folder 4)
  - Stambler, Howard V.
    - "Scientists and Engineers, 1960-1970: Supply and Demand," reprint, Monthly Labor Review, November 1963 (Folder 5)
    - "Still Wanted - Scientists and Engineers," n.d (Folder 6)
  - Stephan, Frederick F., statement before the Subcommittee on Economic Statistics of the Joint Economic Committee, Congress of the United States, May 18, 1967 (Folder 7)
  - Sundquist, James L., "Jobs, Training and Welfare for the Underclass," 1968 (Folder 8)
  - Taylor, Calvin W.
    - "Clues to Creative Teaching," reprint, The Instructor, September 1963 (Folder 9)
    - Creativity: Progress and Potential, n.d., excerpts (Folder 10)
  - Taylor, Geoffrey, "When It Comes to the CRUNCH," reprint, The Public Interest (London), Summer 1968 (Folder 11)
  - Telephone numbers (Folder 12)
  - Travel expenses, 1950-1951 (Folder 13)
  - Tyler, Gus
    - "A Legislative Campaign for a Federal Minimum Wage, 1955," 1959 (Folder 14)
    - "Means and Organization in the Two Periods," n.d. (Folder 15)
  - U.S. Congress. House of Representatives.
    - Committee on Appropriations. Hearings. Rickover, Vice Admiral H. G., "Education for All Children," June 1962 (Folder 16)
    - Committee on Ways and Means. Hearing on Social Security and Welfare Proposals Beginning on October 15, 1969 (Folder 17)
  - U.S. Congress. Joint Economic Committee.
    - "Invention and the Patent System," December 1964 (Folder 18)
    - Subcommittee on Economic Progress, "U.S. Economic Growth to 1975: Potentials and Problems," a study, December 1966 (Folder 19)
    - Subcommittee on Economy in Government, Hearings and Report on the discounting of public investments, July-September 1968 (Folder 20)
  - U.S. defense spending, 1975-1976 (Folder 21)
  - U.S. Department of Agriculture (Box 31.)
    - Agricultural Research Service. Farm Economics Research Division. "Prospects for Adjustments in Production and Resource Use," H. L. Stewart, November 18, 1958 (Folder 1)
    - Forest Service, 1965 (Folder 2)
    - "Organization and Analysis of Program Outputs," George C. Knapp, November 2, 1965 (Folder 3)
  - U.S. Department of the Air Force, DOD Programming System, August 31, 1965 (Folder 4)
  - U.S. Department of Defense, "Planning-Programming-Budgeting System," n.d. (Folder 5)
  - U.S. Department of Health, Education and Welfare. Social Security Administration. Office of Research and Statistics. "Social Security Farm Statistics, 1955-1963," June 1966 (Folder 6)
  - U.S. Department of Labor
    - Bureau of Labor Statistics, "Productivity, Factor Returns, and Price Stability," Jack Alterman, May 1960 (Folder 7)
    - Office of Personnel Administration, Employee Handbook, 1962 (Folder 8)
    - Summary of Manufacturing Earning Series, 1939 - June 1966 (Folder 9)
    - Wage and Labor Standards Administration, "Job Satisfaction," December 12/13, 1966 (Folder 10)
  - U.S. economic assistance (Folder 11)
  - U.S. Economic Survey Mission to the Philippines, Report to the President of the United States, Ocotber 9, 1950 (Folder 12)
  - U.S. foreign relations (Folder 13)
  - U.S. government, policy-influencing personnel (Folder 14)
  - "United States Government Planning-Programming-Budgeting System," n.d. (Folder 15)
  - Walton, Richard R.
    - "The Patent, Trademark, and Copyright Research Institute of the George Washington University," 1967 (Folder 16)
    - Statement before the U.S. Senate Committee on the Judiciary Subcommittee on Antitrust and Monopoly, September 25, 1967 (Folder 17)
  - Ward, Barbara, "Hindsight and Foresight in the World Economy," Columbia Forum, Spring 1969 (Folder 18)
  - Waste disposal (Folder 19)
  - Winston, James S., "A Systems Approach to Training and Development," article, Training and Development Journal, Vol. 22, No. 6, June 1968 (Folder 20)
  - "Economic Assumptions and Outlook: Implications (Guidelines) for Planning Program and Budget in the Department of Labor, Planning Period FY 1970-74," February 27, 1968. Typescript (Box 32., Folder 1)
  - "Economics of Higher Education," July 14, 1969. Typescript (Folder 2)
  - Higher learning, untitled draft on, July 1969. Typescript (photocopy) (Folder 3)
  - "The International Network of Political Labor Unionism," n.d. Typescript (Folder 4)
  - "Minimum Wage for Farm Workers," article, Monthly Labor Review, Vol. 83, No. 7, July 1970. Printed copy (Folder 5)
  - Review of The Two Cultures and the Scientific Revolution by C. P. Snow, October 1960. Magazine article (Folder 6)
  - "Two Decades of the Fair Labor Standards Act," reprint, Monthly Labor Review, October, 1958 (Folder 7)
  - "Work Programs for Adults (Outline)," October 5, 1965. Typescript (Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous drafts and notes (Folder 9-10)